One day, a criminal who was a storyteller
以前有過一個死刑犯，是個說書人
asked to be beheaded in the middle of a storytelling session.
他請求在說書的過程中行刑
My father, Yamada Asaemon Kichiji,
我的父親，山田淺衛門吉次
granted the request.
答應了他的請求
The storyteller ended his act
結果那位說書人最終
with a punch line, as his head fell off.
是在結尾的時候，頭才落地
Even he himself didn't realize he was cut.
就連他本人都沒察覺自己已經被斬首
Free from unnecessary pain and emotion,
那一刀沒有多餘的痛苦跟感情
it was the perfect cut.
是完美的一刀
From that day, my father's sword
自那天起，父親的那一刀
became my goal.
就成了我的目標
What an amazing cut!
真是漂亮的一刀
Though you're a woman, great work.
即使身為女子，刀法卻很出色
Thank you.
過獎了
I see fear…
妳那一刀裡…
in your sword. I see hesitation and fear.
帶有恐懼，恐懼和猶豫
You will let the sinner suffer and die.
會讓犯人在痛苦中死去
I'll do better.
我會加油的
Sagiri, look at your sword.
佐切，看看妳的刀刃
The sword reflects the truth.
刀會反映出真相
A sword weighed down by fear
恐懼會讓刀變得沉重
makes the sinner suffer,
讓犯人更加痛苦
weighing down the sword more.
進而使刀變得更沉重
How can I… How can I have a heart…
怎麼辦？要怎麼做？
with no hesitation and fear?
才能像父親一樣
Like my father.
不猶豫也不害怕？
What if…
真的…
there was a life I could kill
有那種能讓我
without hesitation?
毫不猶豫斬殺的生命嗎？
Welcome, you sinners.
歡迎諸位犯人到此
Here we have, the 11th barbarian general,
坐這裡的這位 是第11代徵夷大將軍
Lord Nariyoshi Tokugawa.
德川齊慶公
He is someone incomparable,
他可是難得一見的大人物
especially to sinners like yourselves.
尤其對你們這種罪犯更是如此
-What the hell? -What nerve you have!
-搞什麼？ -有病嗎？
-Are you kidding me! -Who the hell is this guy?!
-開什麼玩笑？ -將軍是什麼東西？
Is it safe to gather this many criminals?
集結這麼多罪犯真的好嗎？
It's the lord's order.
這是將軍大人的命令
The robber who killed 30 men, Tanio Seikichi
奪走三十條人命的強盜，谷尾清吉
Nikimaru, a serial arsonist.
連續縱火犯，二木丸
A murder accomplice, Kido Shukan.
殺人同心，木戶周監
These are all thugs who caused an uproar in society.
全是惡名昭彰的窮凶極惡之徒
I can't breathe.
我快喘不過氣了
I wanna see Tokugawa in person.
我想親眼見見德川
No, you cannot.
不行
From now, you are all under my orders!
現在我們將授予各位一道密令
You will go to Shinsenkyo,
諸位將前往神仙鄉
and bring back the elixir of immortality.
帶回不老不死的仙藥
The one who succeeds
如有成事者
will receive a full pardon.
就能獲得無罪赦免
Really? Did you hear that?
真的假的？你有聽到嗎？
By the terms of this royal pardon.
拿到這張公儀免罪狀
The atmosphere has changed.
氛圍一下子就變了
With that, I can kill more people again.
拿到的話，就能再次大開殺戒了
Adachi Matagoro,
安達又五郎
A man who killed women and children just for pleasure.
以屠殺婦孺取樂的男人
A man of pure evil. If it's…
徹頭徹尾的惡人，如果是他
a sinner who deserves to die, can I kill him without hesitation?
這種死不足惜的人 我就能沒有迷惘地斬殺他嗎？
Are you Gabimaru the Hollow?
你是伽藍的畫眉丸？
I could tell right away by your hair color and height.
從你的髮色跟身高我就看出來了
You're a big name where we come from.
你在我們的世界裡可是個大名人
But…
不過…
What a disappointment.
真令人失望
You're a lot shorter than they say,
你比傳聞中說的還要矮呢
you're shabby, and short.
不只瘦，還很矮
And you're tied up.
結果跟我們也沒什麼兩樣嘛
Sorry to disappoint you.
讓妳失望了還真是抱歉喔
True, I was a little wary of him at first,
我確實一開始對他也很警惕
but now he's like a different person.
但他現在就像換了一個人
Is he the same as the other sinners?
這個男人也跟其他罪人一樣嗎？
Or is he like the rumors say?
還是他是比傳聞中
Or is he more evil than what they say?
還要更加可惡的邪惡之徒呢？
I will now explain the island where you will be heading to.
接下來，我會說明一下 諸位即將前往的那座島
The island is like a paradise…
島上景色猶如天堂…
-I heard that already! -This is nonsense!
-早就聽過了！ -根本胡說八道！
You reading us a fairytale?
是在讀童話故事嗎？
Remove your papers, you sinners.
把遮面紙拿掉，諸位罪人
I can finally breathe.
終於能呼吸了
He was the only back-up soldier who returned from the recent island survey.
日前前往島上的調查團中 他是唯一生還的士兵
As you can see, he is no longer a person.
如諸位所見，他已是這副非人的模樣
When he returned, he had bumps all over his body.
他回來時，身上長滿了腫瘤
The next day, they blossomed.
隔天，這些腫瘤就開花了
Besides him, sixty odd members of the survey team
除了他之外，餘下六十名調查團成員
are still missing.
至今仍下落不明
What happened on the island?
島上究竟發生了什麼事？
We have no clue since our only witness is in this state.
唯一的情報來源變成這樣 我們也毫無頭緒
No one told us about that!
沒人說過會是這樣子啊
No need to make a fuss.
不需要如此大驚小怪
How mystical and beautiful that a man can turn into a flower.
人的身上能開出花來 也可說是美麗的奇蹟
Especially for sinners like you!
對你們這種罪人來更是難得
What the hell?!
開什麼玩笑啊？
-I'm not going anywhere! -Don't screw with us!
-我哪裡都不去！ -少惹我們！
Enough! You're all condemned to death,
夠了，你們全都是死囚
but you'll be acquitted,
如今不但能獲得赦免
and even be given a chance to go to the Pure Land.
還有機會到淨土一遊
Don't you fools understand
你們怎麼就是不懂
the deep compassion of the court?
將軍大人深厚的恩情呢？
No one knows anything about the island, right?
我們對那座島都是一無所知吧？
What if there's no elixir?
要是根本沒有仙藥呢？
He's right!
他說得對
We can come back empty handed then?
難道我們就兩手空空地回來嗎？
Excuses!
強詞奪理
If you are dissatisfied, you can leave.
不滿的話，想退出也無妨
This is voluntary.
全憑你們的意願
I'm out then. This is creepy.
那我就免了，真噁心
I'd rather die in front of my henchmen waiting for me at the jail--
還不如死在獄中等我的小弟面前…
I forgot to mention one thing.
我漏了一件事
When you go ashore, you will be accompanied by an escort.
諸位登島之後，會有人與各位同行
An escort?
有人同行？
Your death sentence has already been decided.
各位都已經獲判死罪，在劫難逃
The same applies on the island.
在島上自然也不例外
Which means that…
也就是說…
If you make any odd moves on the island,
如果諸位在島上有任何不軌行徑
you will be beheaded on the spot.
就會當場斬立決
Yamada Asaemon will accompany you as watchmen.
山田淺衛門一族將作為監督官隨行
Don't get any funny ideas.
奉勸各位不要打歪主意
Don't forget you're dealing with the Yamada Clan.
你們要面對的可是山田家族
If you turn on them, you will end up like him.
如果膽敢對他們出手 就會落得這般下場
If you kill your escort intentionally,
諸位如果蓄意謀殺監督官
or by accident, you will be beheaded.
或是意外導致他們死亡 也一樣當場斬首
You will not be allowed on the return trip
回程如果沒有監督官同行
unless you are accompanied by an escort.
你們就不能登船
-Is that true? -Yes.
-是真的嗎？ -沒錯
I see.
這樣啊
This guy…
這傢伙
Does he have balls or does he not?
到底是有種還是沒種？
Hey, come here!
過來
Ok, yes sir.
是
Sorry, I have one more thing.
抱歉，還有一件事要說
We need to narrow down the number before we leave for the island.
出發前，我們需要減少人數
Not everyone will be able to land on the island.
不是所有人都能登上那座島
The capacity of the ship and
畢竟船的承載量有限
the number of watchmen are limited.
也沒有那麼多人能當監督官
So I need you to narrow down the number of people now.
所以現在必須縮減人數
Narrow down?
縮減人數？
You don't get it, do you?
聽不懂是吧？
In other words…
換句話說
Get rid of the wimps right here, right now. Correct?
雜碎現在就得解決掉，是吧？
What the hell are you doing?
你幹什麼？
Look.
看啊
The fact that he's not saying anything proves it.
我這麼做了，他也沒出聲制止啊
He's telling us to kill each other!
這就是要我們自相殘殺
You'll die if you're too slow.
動作太慢可是會死掉的喔
Well, it can't be helped if you take it that way.
如果你要這麼想的話，那我也沒辦法
If you die here,
會死在這裡的話
it means you're useless anyway.
也是沒有用的廢物
Oh, and don't take off your ropes.
對了，不能掙脫繩索喔
This is it!
就是要這樣
In this day and age, it's not every day
這個世道可是很難見到
that you have to risk your life in a fight.
要冒死爭搶的戰鬥呢
I've always wanted to see something like this.
我一直都很想親眼看看
What a fool this man is.
真是個愚蠢的老傢伙
What's the point in doing this anyway?
做這種事有什麼意義？
You can't fight a man being tied.
手被綁住，不能隨心所欲地戰鬥
Tangled and entrapped…
這種糾纏混戰…
Everyone's going to end up being useless.
最後所有人都會變成沒用的傢伙
Who are the ones marked with the red ink?
那些蓋了朱印的是什麼人？
Among the sinners,
在那些罪人之中
those with extraordinary abilities.
有些人有不同於常人的能力
They are men who are truly worthy
甚至有的人
of being called "extraordinary."
還因此被稱為“異能者”
Those marked with the red ink
這些人都被標上了朱印
are for example, him.
比如說這個人
A young man who led a band of thieves,
年紀輕輕就率領一幫盜賊
and established a village of thieves deep in the Mountains of Iyo.
在伊予的深山 建立了賊人的村落，是謂豪傑
That woman was the criminal
而那邊那個女的
in last year's Sagiba Castle invasion riot.
是去年鷺羽城入侵事件的元凶
She's a woman ninja
是僅憑一人之力
who subdued every single vassal in the castle.
幹掉所有家臣的女忍者
The great swordsman known as "Sword Dragon" or "Eight State Warrior."
那位則是譽為 “劍龍”和“八州無雙”的大劍豪
A giant man who is said to eat a bear from it's head.
那位巨漢能將一頭熊從頭吞下肚
Neither a sword or a spear could scrape him.
據說他的身體可謂刀槍不入
This is like a picture scroll of the Warring States Period.
簡直就像戰國繪卷嘛
The main highlight is the living legend,
其中最值得一看的就是活生生的傳說
Gabimaru the Hollow.
伽藍的畫眉丸
He's right over there.
就在那邊
Hm? He's not moving at all.
他一動也不動的
The legendary…?
那個傳說中的…
Is the pressure getting to you, Sagiri?
有壓力了嗎，佐切？
Lord Eizen.
衛善閣下
It's going to be harsher once we're on the island.
登島之後情勢會更加嚴峻
Not only between the criminals,
不只是罪犯自身
but your life is at risk too.
妳自己也身處險境
When that happens, can you slay them?
面臨生死關頭時 妳還能斬殺他們嗎？
Let me tell you this since I have the chance.
既然事已至此，我就藉此把話說清楚
This job is not for you.
妳根本就不適合當御用試刀人
Why would a woman go to the trouble of wielding a sword?
身為女人，有什麼必要揮刀？
If you are a daughter of a samurai family, you should live quietly in your palace.
一個生在武士世家的女兒 在家裡安安靜靜地生活就好
And live a life far from a beheading executioner.
根本無需成為斬首行刑人
With all due respect, Lord Eizen.
恕我直言，衛善閣下
If I could have done so, I would have.
可以的話 我也希望像你說的那樣生活
In addition to test cutting with human bodies,
除了用活人試刀的御用試刀人之外
beheadings, and the making of medicine using the human corpse.
斬首行刑，以及使用人類屍身製藥
Even if you didn't wield a sword, if you were born into the Yamada family,
只要生在山田家，就算不揮刀
you feed on the death of others.
也得憑藉他人的死亡求存
Take that!
打死妳！
It's the daughter of Asa the Decapitator!
是斬首淺家的女兒！
The daughter of the cannibal Asa!
是食人淺家的女兒！
Murderer!
殺人犯！
Come out!
給我出來！
Take that!
丟她！
No matter how much you turn away…
不管多想閉上雙眼不去面對…
The truth is reflected in the sword.
刀依舊會反映出真相
We've got no choice.
根本沒機會嘛
Let's break through these samurai and get out of here!
我們一起突破這群武士逃出去吧
Brother!
大哥
That samurai over there is a woman!
那邊那個武士是個女的
Let's kill her and take her sword!
先幹掉她，搶走她的劍
Can you slay him?
妳能砍他嗎？
I can't escape from the beheader's work.
我無法逃離斬首人的工作
If so…
既然如此…
I can't just sit back and accept it.
我就不能坐以待斃，默默承受
I won't!
絕對不能！
I want to judge
我的所作所為
my own actions for myself.
我要自己下評斷！
Why?
為什麼？
Why do you think it's okay to kill people?
你們怎麼會以為殺了人 還能若無其事？
Can't you think of another way?
難道就不能換個方式嗎？
How did you…? Get back!
你是什麼時候…退下！
Not all murderers like to kill.
不是所有殺人犯都喜歡殺人
What are the guards doing?
守衛兵在幹什麼？
How can anyone stand this?
誰有辦法忍受這種事啊？
How rude of you to speak to the Lord in that way!
竟敢出言頂撞將軍大人，真是無禮！
I would prefer not to kill.
不是啊…可以的話，我就不想殺人
Isn't that a normal thought.
這樣想不是很正常的事嗎？
What is an outlaw like you saying?
你這種罪人說這什麼話？
If you don't like it, leave it.
不喜歡的話就放棄免罪狀啊
That's all.
就這樣而已
You don't get it.
你果然不懂
Hey, you guys over there.
喂，那邊的傢伙
Kill him and you'll be on the landing party.
殺掉他，你們就可以登船了
Seriously?
真的嗎？
Don't move.
好好在待在那裡不准動
You don't want to kill for nothing, do you?
不是，你們也不想做無謂的殺生吧？
I don't mind. If I can survive,
只要能活下來，我才不在乎
I'd be glad to kill you.
我很樂意幹掉你
-Don't avoid it! -Why don't we talk?
-不要躲開啊 -為什麼不能好好談談？
If you don't want to fight, just shut up and die!
不想打的話，就閉嘴受死吧
I have no choice.
沒辦法了
I'll have to kill you.
只能殺人了
If you're going to kill me,
你打算殺了我的話，我就只能殺掉你
I thought you didn't want that.
我…我以為你不想殺人的
I don't. But…
是不想，只不過…
I can't die either.
我也不能死
I have no choice.
那就沒辦法了
What the hell are you saying?
你到底在說什麼啊？
My heart feels heavy,
想到之後要背負的東西
when I think about what I will have to bear.
我就感覺很沉重啊
I don't want to do this. I really don't.
我不想殺人，真的不想
What a monster!
他根本是個怪物啊
So that is…
這就是…
the Hollow.
伽藍堂
My heart feels heavy…
想到之後要背負的東西
when I think about what I will have to bear.
我就感覺很沉重啊
What a cruel and brutal way to kill someone.
真是殘忍粗暴的殺人手法
If I did it nicely, would they not hate me?
難道動手溫柔點就不會被怨恨了嗎？
What I needed was…
我所需要的
not the strength to fear killing.
並非不懼砍殺的力量
But to be prepared to bear that fear,
而是做好承擔這份恐懼
to bear the lives of those I've killed.
承擔手上殺孽的覺悟
Sagiri, are you okay?
佐切，沒事吧？
Maybe this job is too much for you.
這份工作對妳來說果然太沉重了
No, sir. I will kill him.
不會，他就由我來斬殺
That's enough, sinners!
到此為止了，罪人們
You are hereby declared the landing party.
自此你們就是登島組了
The Bandit King, Aza Chobei.
盜賊首領，亞左弔兵衛
The Blade Dragon, Tamiya Gantetsusai.
“劍龍”，民谷嚴鐵齋
Hunter of the Hundred, Warped Keiun.
“百本授”，歪之慶雲
Nurugai of the Mountains.
“山民”，濡垓
Killing Buddha, Horubo.
“殺人念佛”，法流坊
Rogue Ninja, Gabimaru the Hollow.
逃忍，伽藍的畫眉丸
Cannibal Courtesan, Akaginu. Yuzuriha of Keishu.
“食人花魁”，赤絹 女忍，“傾主之槓”
The Apostate, Moro Makiya.
改教教徒，茂籠木耶
The Giant of Bizen, Rokurota.
“備前大巨”，陸郎太
The above ten shall be the members.
以上共十位
Each member will be accompanied
每一位身邊
by one of the disciples of the Yamada Clan,
都會派一位山田門下的
a beheader of Asaemon will accompany you.
斬首行刑人隨行
You will now board the ship,
現在諸位即將登船
and head to a secluded island in the South Sea,
前往南海的秘境之島
to search for the elixir of immortality.
尋找不老不死的仙藥
If you find it, you are free.
找到的人就可重獲自由
No need to worry.
不用擔心
The destination is the pure land of paradise.
那裡是極樂淨土
The land of everlasting life, Shinsenkyo.
人稱“常世之國”的神仙鄉
There is no danger!
沒有任何危險！
Subtitle translation by: Mel Nishi
字幕翻譯：洪貞韻